export default {
  id: 'mid_3a',
  name: '상용한자(중학3/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '揚', answer: ['날릴 양, 높일 양', 'あ(げる)、あ(がる)', 'よう'] },
    { question: '瘍', answer: ['종기 양, 상처 양', '종기, 상처', 'よう'] },
    { question: '恒', answer: ['항상 항', '항상', 'こう'] },
    { question: '垣', answer: ['담 원', 'かき', ''] },
    { question: '伯', answer: ['맏 백, 우두머리 백', '맏, 우두머리', 'はく'] },
    { question: '拍', answer: ['칠 박', '칠', 'はく、[ひょう]'] },
    { question: '泊', answer: ['묵을 박', 'と(まる)、と(める)', 'はく'] },
    { question: '舶', answer: ['큰 배 박', '큰 배', 'はく'] },
    { question: '迫', answer: ['닥칠 박', 'せま(る)', 'はく'] },
    { question: '腺', answer: ['샘 선', '샘', 'せん'] },
    { question: '棚', answer: ['선반 붕', 'たな', ''] },
    { question: '崩', answer: ['무너질 붕', 'くず(れる)、くず(す)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '蛇', answer: ['뱀 사', 'へび', 'じゃ、だ'] },
    { question: '繭', answer: ['고치 견', 'まゆ', 'けん'] },
    { question: '旨', answer: ['맛 지', 'むね', 'し'] },
    { question: '脂', answer: ['기름 지', 'うぶら', 'し'] },
    { question: '詣', answer: ['이를 예', 'もう(でる)', 'けい'] },
    { question: '鎮', answer: ['누를 진, 진압할 진', 'しず(める)、しず(まる)', 'ちん'] },
    { question: '填', answer: ['채울 전', '채울', 'てん'] },
    { question: '慎', answer: ['삼갈 신', 'つつし(む)', 'しん'] },
    { question: '罷', answer: ['마칠 파', '마칠', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '熊', answer: ['곰 웅', 'くま', ''] },
    { question: '昆', answer: ['맏 곤, 벌레 곤', '맏, 벌레', 'こん'] },
    { question: '皆', answer: ['다 개', 'みな', 'かい'] },
    { question: '諧', answer: ['어울릴 해', '어울릴', 'かい'] },
    { question: '楷', answer: ['본보기 해', '본보기', 'かい'] },
    { question: '鹿', answer: ['사슴 록', 'しか、[か]', ''] },
    { question: '麓', answer: ['산기슭 록', 'ふもと', 'ろく'] },
    { question: '麗', answer: ['고울 려, 빛날 려', 'うるわ(しい)', 'れい'] },
    { question: '慶', answer: ['경사 경', '경사', 'けい'] },
    { question: '薦', answer: ['추천할 천', 'すす(める)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '靴', answer: ['가죽신 화', 'くつ', 'か'] },
    { question: '覇', answer: ['으뜸 패', '으뜸', 'は'] },
    { question: '環', answer: ['고리 환', '고리', 'かん'] },
    { question: '還', answer: ['돌아올 환', '돌아올', 'かん'] },
    { question: '娠', answer: ['임신 신', '임신', 'しん'] },
    { question: '振', answer: ['떨칠 진, 흔들 진', 'ふ(る)、ふ(るう)、ふ(れる)', 'しん'] },
    { question: '唇', answer: ['입술 순', 'くちびる', 'しん'] },
    { question: '震', answer: ['벼락 진, 진동할 진', 'ふる(う)、ふる(える)', 'しん'] },
    { question: '辱', answer: ['욕될 욕', 'はずかし(める)', 'じょく'] },
    { question: '濃', answer: ['짙을 농', 'こい', 'のう'] },
    { question: '曹', answer: ['무리 조', '무리', 'そう'] },
    { question: '槽', answer: ['통 조', '통', 'そう'] },
    { question: '遭', answer: ['만날 조, 당할 조', 'あ(う)', 'そう'] },
    { question: '艶', answer: ['고울 염', 'つや', 'えん'] },
    { question: '刈', answer: ['벨 예', 'かる', ''] },
    { question: '刹', answer: ['짧은시간 찰, 절 찰', '짧은시간, 절', 'さつ、せつ'] },
    { question: '凶', answer: ['흉할 흉', '흉할', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '爽', answer: ['시원할 상', 'さわ(やか)', 'そう'] },
    { question: '璽', answer: ['옥새 새, 도장 새', '옥새, 도장', 'じ'] },
    { question: '璃', answer: ['유리 리', '유리', 'り'] },
    { question: '離', answer: ['헤어질 리', 'はな(れる)、はな(す)', 'り'] },
    { question: '絞', answer: ['목맬 교', 'し(ぼる)、し(める)、し(まる)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '較', answer: ['비교할 교', 'かく', ''] },
    { question: '郊', answer: ['교외 교', '교외', 'こう'] },
    { question: '砕', answer: ['부술 쇄', 'くだ(く)、くだ(ける)', 'さい'] },
    { question: '粋', answer: ['순수할 수', 'いき', 'すい'] },
    { question: '酔', answer: ['취할 취', 'よう', 'すい'] },
    { question: '蚊', answer: ['모기 문', 'か', ''] },
    { question: '紋', answer: ['무늬 문', '무늬', 'もん'] },
    { question: '斑', answer: ['얼룩 반', '얼룩', 'はん'] },
    { question: '依', answer: ['의지할 의', '의지할', 'い、[え]'] },
    { question: '喪', answer: ['초상 상, 잃을 상', 'も', 'そう'] },
    { question: '哀', answer: ['슬플 애', 'あわ(れ)、あわ(れむ)', 'あい'] },
    { question: '衰', answer: ['쇠할 쇠, 상복 최', 'おとろ(える)', 'すい'] },
    { question: '衷', answer: ['속마음 충', '속마음', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '猿', answer: ['원숭이 원', 'さる', 'えん'] },
    { question: '褒', answer: ['기릴 포', 'ほ(める)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '巾', answer: ['수건 건', '수건', 'きん'] },
    { question: '錦', answer: ['비단 금', 'にしき', 'きん'] },
    { question: '帥', answer: ['장수 수', '장수', 'すい'] },
    { question: '柿', answer: ['감 시', 'かき', ''] },
    { question: '滞', answer: ['막힐 체', 'とどこお(る)', 'たい'] },
    { question: '怖', answer: ['두려워할 포', 'こわ(い)', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '飾', answer: ['꾸밀 식', 'かざ(る)', 'しょく'] },
    { question: '僚', answer: ['동료 료', '동료', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '瞭', answer: ['밝을 료', '밝을', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '寮', answer: ['집 료, 동료 료', '집, 동료', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '療', answer: ['병고칠 료', '병고칠', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '眉', answer: ['눈썹 미', 'まゆ', 'び、[み]'] },
    { question: '盲', answer: ['장님 맹', '장님', 'もう'] },
    { question: '眠', answer: ['잘 면', 'ねむ(る)、ねむ(い)', 'みん'] },
    { question: '恨', answer: ['한할 한', 'うらむ、うらめしい', 'こん'] },
    { question: '痕', answer: ['흔적 흔', 'あと', 'こん'] },
    { question: '娘', answer: ['아가씨 낭', 'むすめ', ''] },
    { question: '浪', answer: ['물결 랑', '물결', 'ろう'] },
    { question: '郎', answer: ['사내 랑', '사내', 'ろう'] },
    { question: '廊', answer: ['행랑 랑', '행랑', 'ろう'] },
    { question: '寛', answer: ['너그러울 관', '너그러울', 'かん'] },
    { question: '餌', answer: ['먹이 이', 'えさ、え', 'じ'] },
    { question: '恥', answer: ['부끄러울 치', 'は(じる)、は(じ)、は(じらう)、は(ずかしい)', 'ち'] },
    { question: '摂', answer: ['끌어당길 섭, 알맞게할 섭', '끌어당길, 알맞게할', 'せつ'] },
    { question: '趣', answer: ['재미 취', 'おもむき', 'しゅ'] },
    { question: '撮', answer: ['사진찍을 촬', 'と(る)', 'さつ'] },
    { question: '憂', answer: ['근심할 우', 'うれ(え)る、うれ(い)、う(い)', 'ゆう'] },
    { question: '臭', answer: ['냄새 취', 'くさ(い)、にお(う)', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '嗅', answer: ['냄새맡을 후', 'か(ぐ)', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '冒', answer: ['무릅쓸 모', 'おか(す)', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '帽', answer: ['모자 모', '모자', 'ぼう'] }
  ]
}
